Guide to the Henry Taube Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-008
  - Former Associates
    - Beyerle-Pinur, Rut (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Bino, Avi – Visiting Scholar (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Bossard, Gerald E., Postdoc February 1982 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Bowen,. A. Randall (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Breckenridge, William H. (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Blesa, Miguel A. (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Broomhead, John A., 1967-83 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Brown, Gilbert post-doc, 1974-97 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Brulet, Christa (Schenk), 1971-75 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Buhr, John, 1978-97 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Butler, Ronald Dean, 1961-68 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Burness, James H., 1974 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Cahill, Alan E., (includes photographs) 1962-78 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Clark, Michael J., 1970-97 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Cordone, Rossella, 1980-88 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Creutz, Carol, 1968-99 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Czapski, Gidon (Visiting Scholar), 1982-85 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Deutsch, Edward A., 1963-95 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Diamond, Steve, 1975-94 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Diaz, Hector, 1968-81 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Diebler, Hartmut, 1962-74 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Dobson, John C., 1986-89 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Dong, Teng-Yuan, postdoc research affiliate, 1985-91 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Donham, Donald Lewis, 1968-71 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Dosza, Laszlo, postdoc, 1978-97 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Dosza, Laszlo, Spectra graphs (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Droege, Michael, 1984-86 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Dunne, Thomas G., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Edwards, John, visiting scholar, 1975-82 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Endicott, John Frederick, 1962-99 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Escobar, Marta, 1982-85 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Espenson, James H., 1962-95 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Fairlie, David P, postdoc, 1983-2001 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Fischer, Helmut (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Fontal, Bernardo (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Ford, Peter C. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - French, James E. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Frye, James (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Flamberg, Pearl (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Flamberg, Pearl (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Flood, Michael (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Franco, Douglas (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Frye, James (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Gaswick, Dennis (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Gaunder, Robert (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Geselowitz, Daniel (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Gilberg, Mark (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Ghosh, Phalguni (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Gould, Edwin Shelton (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Green, Michael (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Gutterman, Diane (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Haas, Otto (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Hagen, Karl S. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Haim, Albert (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Haim, Albert (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Hammershoi, Anders (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Harman, Dean 1 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Harman, Dean 2 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Harman, Dean 3 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Harman, Dean 4 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Harrigan, Raymond (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Harrison, David E. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Heckman, Karen Sue (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Henry, Patrick M. Sabbatical Jan. 1978 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Herman, Zelek Seymour (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Holwerda, Robert (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Hoffman, Bruce A. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Hou, Doug (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Hu, Dongqi (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Hung, Yam (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Hunt, John Baker (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Hunt, John P. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Huchital, Daniel H. (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Hurst, James K. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Ilan, Yigal (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Isied, Stephan 1 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Isied, Stephan 2 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Iverson, Daniel (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Johnson, Arden (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Jones, Patrick Ray (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Jordan, Robert Beatty (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Katakis, Demetrius (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Kirchner, Karl (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Kobuek, Edward – Sabbatical – US Naval Academy, 1970-72 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Krentzien, Heinz, 1972-82 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kuhn, Christa, 1971-97 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Kuempel, John R, Postdoc, 1967-72 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Kugel, Roger W., 1974-84 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Kung, Jenny Wei-Jen, postdoc, 1975-83 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Kwan, Keh-Shin Alexander, postdoc, 1980-91 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Lau, Tai-Chu, Postdoc, 1982-2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Lay, Peter, Postdoc 1982, 1980-1999 [4 folders] (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Lewis, Nita A, 1977-2002 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Li, Zaiwei, 1988-1997 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Li, Zaiwei Research Folder (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Lee, Kuan-Hua (Tom), 1979-91 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Linck, Robert G., 1962-81 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Loeliger, David A., 1961-1988 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Ludi, Andreass, 1975-2001 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Lyon, John M., Postdoctoral, 1982-1991 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Maeda, Hiroyuki, 1993-94 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Malin, John, 1971-1991 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Magnuson, Roy H., 1973-81 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Mandelin, Dorothy (Bearcraft), 1966-84 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Maspero, Federico (Postdoc), 1965-68 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Matwiyoff, Nicholas, 1963-67 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - McQueen, J Scott, 1995-99 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Meyer, James W., 1969-71 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Meyer, Thomas J, 1966-2000 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Milburn, Ronald McRae, 1963-88 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Mohammed, Dr. Mahboob Visiting Scholar Sept. 1984 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Nagao, Noriharu (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Nelson, Russell Everett Jr. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Niac, Gavril (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Niac, G. et al. Chromate and Thiosulfate (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Nicouletopoulos, Petros (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Nord, Gwyneth (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Nordmeyer, Francis R (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Norris, A. R. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Nunes, Fabio (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Ogard, Al (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Olson, Maynard V. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Otonari, Yoshiko (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Pendergast, Warren (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Persson, Ingmar (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Pinsky, Barry post-doc 1978 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Barry Pinsky (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Barry Pinsky (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Pladziewicz, John R (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Po, Henry. Sabattical, Cal State University, Spr. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Price, Harry James (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Pu, Lin (1) (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Pu, Lin (2) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Pu, Lin (3) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Pu, Lin (4) (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Quarles, Richard W. Jr (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Raichart, Dennis W (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Rieder, Konrad (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Rich, Donald (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Richardson, David (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Roberts, E. Kirk (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Robson, Richard (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Rudd, DeForest P. (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Sano, Mitsuru (1) 1997-2002 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Sano, Mitsuru (2) 1994-97 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Sano, Mitsuru (3) 1986-94 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sano, Mitsuru (4) 1988-92 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sargeson, Alan McLeod (1) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Sargeson, Alan McLeod (2) includes photograph (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Schaeffer, Lauge. September, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Scheidegger, Hans A. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Schmidt, Wilfred G (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Schwabacher, William B (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Schweier, Gunther (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Scott, Napapon S., Post Doc 9/1/79-9/1/80 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Sekine, Mikiya (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Sheperd, Rex A Jr. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Shugarman, Arnold (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Sen, Judith (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Sibbett, Scott (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Sleiman, Hanadi (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Smith, Terence P., Post Doc Apr 1982 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Spiro, Cliff. Undergraduate (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Stanbury, David M. (1) (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Stanbury, David M. (2) (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Stein paper, National Academy of Sciences (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Stein, Cy A. (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Storm, Carlyle B. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Stritar, Jeffrey Allen. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Sullivan, James C. Visiting Scholar (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Sundberg, Richard J (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Sutton, James (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Sutton, Patrick (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Swinehart, James H (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Tanna, Charlotte H (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Tjok, Pweh-Boon (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Thusius, Darwin Dean (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Tom, Glenn (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Toma, Enrique (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Tweedle, Michael F., Post Doc Sept. 1977 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Valentine, Donald (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Viste, Arlen E (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - v. Kameke, Allard (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Walker, Darrel D. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Wang, Renyi (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Ware, David (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Weissberger, Edward (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - White, James Dee (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - White, James Dee (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Willis, Michael (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Wilson, Charles R (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Winkler, Jay (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Wishart, James (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Wong, Ching-Ping, Post Doc (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Yamamoto, Haruhiko (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Yamamoto, Yasuo, Post-doc (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Yeh, Andrew, Postdoctoral (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Zabin, Burton Allen (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Zanella, Andrew (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Zawacky, Susan (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Susan Zawacky – Seminar Folder (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Ziolkowski, Jozef (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Zwickel, Allen (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Taube reprints (Box 13)
    - Comparisons of the Rates of Substitution in [Ru(NH3)5H2O]3+. V Poulopoulou and Z-W Li (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Structure of the First Stable Ethene-Ethyne Metal…Pu, Hasegawa, Parkin and Taube (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Reudction of [OS(NH3)5(n2-CH3CH=NH2)…Haegawa, Kwan, Taube (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Use of a Dihydrogen Osmium Complex as a Versatile H NMR Recognition Probe. Li and Taube (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Substitution Inducted N-N Coupling. Ware and Taube (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Facile Nucleophilic Substitution on Coordinated…Kirchner and Taube (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Electronic Effects of Bis(acetylacetone) in Ruthenium(II) and Ruthenium(III) Complexes, Taube and others (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Aspects of n2 binding by Osmiumammines (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - The Study of the Reactivity of Transition Metal Complexes, Taube (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Molecular Hysteresis, Sano and Taube (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Solvent Effects on the Reactivity of Vanadium(II) John C Dobson and Mitsuru Sano (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Allyn Complexes of Pentaammineosmium. W Dean Harman and Tai Hasegawa (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Preparation and Characterization of a Bispentaammineosmium (II) Pyrnene… Hasegawa, Sekine, and Schaefer (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Reactions of Hexachloroosmate(IV)with Hydrazine Hydrate: Syntheses and Properties of Pentaammine(dinitrogen)… Lay and Taube (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Effects on the Frequency and Intensity of the Streching Vibration… Johnson and Taube (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Isostructural n2-Dihydrogen Complexes (Os(NH3)5(H2))n+… WD Harman (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Crystal Structure and Pyrolysis of [(OS(NH3)5)2… Harman, Gebhard, Taube (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - The Regio-and Stereospecific Selective Hydrogenation of … W Dean Harman, William P Schaefer (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Synthesis of Pentaammineosmium(III) and osmium (II) Complexes… Lay, Magnuson, and Taube (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - n Heterocyclic Complexes of Pentaammineosmium(II) and the Metal Induced… Cordone, Harman, and Taube (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Arene to Alkyne Linkage Isomerizations of Diphenylacetylene on Pentaammineosmium. Harman, Wishart, and Taube (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Alkyne Addition Reactions of Pentaammine-osmium(II). The Formation of… Harman, Dobson, Taube (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Chemistry 251, Problem Set #5 – 1976 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Carbon-Hydrogen Bond Activation in Novel… Cordone, Harman, Taube (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Nitrile Complexes of Pantaammineosmium(II) and (III) Sekine, Harman, and Taube (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - N Localization in Aromatic Ligands… Formation of Mixed Metal.. Harman and Taube (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Selective Hydrogenation of Benzene to Cyclohexene on Pentaammineosmium (II), 1988 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Electron Transfer through Macromolecular Systems, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Substituent Effects on n2-Coordinate Arene Complexes of Pentaammineosmium(II). Harman, Sekine, and Taube (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Redox-Coupled Linkage Isomerizations with n2 Coordinated Anilines, Harman and Taube (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Redox Catalyzed Condensation of Hexaammineosmium(II) with Acetone, Harman and Taube (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Synthesis of N Heterocyclic Complexes of Osmium, Ruthenium, Cobalt, and Rhodium… Lay, Magnuson, Taube (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Pyrazine-Bridged Complexes. Synthesis of and Spectroscopic Studies on Binuclear Pyrazine Complexes of Osmium, Ruthenium, and Rhodium Ammines, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - Unfoldered materials [possibly class files] (Box 13)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize) 1983-84 (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize 1983 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize 1983 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize) 1983-84 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize) 1983-84 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize) 1983-84 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize) 1983-84 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Unsorted correspondence (congratulatory letters on Nobel Prize) 1983-84 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Class files
    - Chemistry 181, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Chemistry 251, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Chemistry 153 mid-term exam, Feb. 1972 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Chemistry 153: 1982 Wishart's Notes (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Chemistry 153: 1985 Course and Class Notes (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Lecture for Ed Solomon by H.T., undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Chemistry 137 final exam, spring quarter 1974 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Chemistry 137, 1974-76 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Chemistry 150, lecture notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Electron Transfer Course Material (notes) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Chemistry 151, 1980-81 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Chemistry 153, 1973-82 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Chemistry 180, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Chemistry 151, notes (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Chemistry 151 and 153 Holm material, 1978-79 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Chemistry 151 or 153, lecture notes (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Chem 153 – Solvent Effects Chemistry, lecture notes (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Class notes unlabelled (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Chemistry 153 notes (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Chemistry 253, 1978-82 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Chemistry 302, 1947-59 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Chemistry 301, 1946-59 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Chemistry 302 Notes (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Chemistry 153, 1983-84 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Lecture files
    - Notes, miscellaneous [Milne Complex – Dyno (?)] (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Baker Lectures (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Chemical Reactivity (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Conference [notes] (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Back Bonding Etc [notes, reprints, unsigned letter 1977] (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Canterbury (Internatl. Symposium on the Mechanisms of Reactions in Solution) - illustrations from a talk ?, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Oxygen Reduction text, St Louis, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Oxygen Exchange for Carboxylate Complexes, notes (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - O3 Chemistry – notes, reprint 1957, letter from Dmitri (Brookhaven Lab) 1961 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Oxidation-Reduction by Electron Transfer Through Molecules – outline and notes (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Ohio State lecture – outline and notes, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - O17 nmr work, notes (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - MIT-Harvard lecture, notes (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Miami lecture, outline, April 1967 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Iowa 1, 3405 [indirect electron transfer notes] (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Ion solvation, notes (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Inorganic Reactions, Wilmington talk, outline (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - HO Radical, notes (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Wilmington (lecture notes?) (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Influence of Metal Ions on Reactivity, notes (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Harrison Howe Lecture, November 1960 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Hercules Inc. – research notes 1973 and undated (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Gordon conference, notes, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Gordon Research Conf, New Hampton, 1967 (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Productivity in Research, typescript (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Reactions of Oxy Ions, notes and typescript chapter (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Lectures – Piridynyl Radicals (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence (some re winning Nobel Prize 1983; one outgoing letter re airline trouble, 1974) (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - Rare(?) emitters in molten salts - notes (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Recording and Historical Records (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Reed College Lectures, June 1962 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - USC Lecture April 1967 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Baker Lectures (Cornell) (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - North Jersey Section Talk – March 10, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Creativity in Science (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Ghent, Belgium 1968. Electron Transfer in Solution (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - 1 vs 2e Changes (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Induced electron transfer - notes (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Experiments with C1 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Electron Transfer Lecture (ACS Meeting, Los Angeles, April 1974) (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Electron Transfer General (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Electron Transfer UWO (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - YL Ions (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Invitations – Declined, 1984-89 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Visitors and Seminar Speakers, Taube, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Visitors and Seminar Speakers, Taube, 1979-1980 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Travel and Lectures, Taube, 1977-78 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Travel and Lectures, Taube, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Travel and Lectures, Taube, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Research files
    - Ghosh, Sutapa. Notebook: molecular replacement, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - V-py affinity (graphs, charts, notes) (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - V-py affinity 2 (graphs, charts, notes) (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Recent Data (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Unlabeled (graphs, charts, notes) (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Two proposals: one by Phalguni Ghosh and one unsigned (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Taube reprints (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Unlabeled (graphs, charts, notes) (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Unlabeled (overhead projection slides) (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - UV-VIS (charts) (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Colleague reprint files with correspondence
    - Aprile (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Bray, Wm. D. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Endicott, John (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Fronaeus, S. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Ann Lee (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Reprints [also possibly: Colleague reprint files with correspondence]
    - Reprints of Taube articles (Box 16, Folder 6-15)
  - Travel records
    - Travel records from binder, 1987-1989 (Box 16, Folder 16-18)
    - Travel records from binder, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 19-20)
    - Travel records from binder, 1991-1992 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Travel records from binder, 1991-1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Travel records from binder, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 2-3)
  - Research files: correspondence, papers, etc.
    - Instrument data from binder (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - ACS 95.4 Endiyne (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Dr. Tsuzuki (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - N2 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Prof. Yamagishi (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Superconductor (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Optical Separation (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Unknown Chinese (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Amino Acid + M (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Taube Lab (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Os2PYRN paper (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Ru(Acac)2L2­, L=PPH3, CO (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - N=C Papers (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - OS(IV)-Ally1 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - PKa (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Lin (2) (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Lin #3 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Lin #3 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Paper 3 (JCS) (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Loose papers and notebooks (Box 17)
    - Taube Group hazardous materials guide and safety manual (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Lab facilities (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Olinonucleotides (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Crossed out (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - No label (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - No label (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - X-Ray Neutron Structure (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Scrapbook, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem (1979 honorary degree to Taube) (Box 18)
  - Certificate, Southern Illinois University (Box 18)
  - Scroll (Japanese or Chinese, in wooden box) (Box 18)
  - Printing die: portrait of Taube (Box 18)
  - Henry Taube, Friedman Lecture, Brooklyn College 3/19/86, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 18)
  - The Robert A. Welch Foundation AVW 12-19-83, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 18)
  - Taube's name stamp (Box 18)
  - RESTRICTED
    The materials are restricted.
    - Murray, Michele undergraduate (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Restricted for 75 years.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2005-081
  - Isomeric Forms of the Complexes of Tetraammineruthenium (III) and (II) with Glycylamide and Derivatives manuscript, typescript, correspondence, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Isonitrile as a Ligand on Ruthenium (II) Amines - manuscript, typescript, correspondence, 1981-82 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Affinity of Tetraammineruthenium (II) and (III) for Some Amino Acid Esters - manuscript, typescript, correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Shugarman, et. al. [Oxidation of Glyoxylatopentaaminecobalt (III) by Chromium (VI)] - manuscript, typescript, correspondence, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aquo Chemistry of Monoarene Complexes of Os(II) and Ru(III) – typescript, correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Intramolecular Electron Transfer Reactions in Bridged Binuclear Ru(III) – Co(III) Molecules – typescript, published copy, correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - N-Macrocyclic Complexes of Ruthenium(II) and Ruthenium(III) - manuscript, typescript, correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Affinity of Aquopentaammine ruthenium(II) and (III) for Esters of Amino Acids - manuscript, typescript, correspondence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Superoxide Reactions with Isonicotinamidepentammine-ruthenium(II) and (III) – typescripts, correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Metal to Metal Interactions in Weakly Coupled Mixed Valence Complexes Based on Ruthenium Ammines – typescripts, correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Binuclear Mixed Valence Rutheniumammine Complexes with t-Butylmalonodinitrile as Bridging Ligand – grafts, correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Reactions of Pentaammineruthenium Complexes, etc. – typescripts, correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Autoxidation of Binuclear Ruthenium(II) Ammines – typescripts, correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Coordination chemistry of Polypyridyl Complexes of Vanadium in Non-protic Solvents [notes on transparencies] – Los Angeles ACS 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Haverford #2 – Electron Transfer – Gen. [transparencies] (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gelelowitz work (film slides) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - [unlabeled slides] (Box 2, Folder 9)